Guide to the Whole Earth Catalog Records, 1969-1986 (bulk 1974-1980)
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1. Stewart Brand Editorial files
  - Subseries 2. Mickey Mouse lawsuit
    - Walt Disney Regarding Mickey Mouse 1979 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 3. Subject files
    - Co-Evolution Quarterly: Promotional Materials (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Co-Evolution Quarterly (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Reviews of "News that Stayed News:" Ten Years of the Co-evolution Quarterly (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Whole Earth Software Review/ Whole Earh Software Catalog (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Whole Earth Review/ Whole Earh Software Catalog: samples (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Whole Earh Software Catalog [1 of 5] 1984 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Whole Earh Software Catalog [2 of 5] 1984 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Whole Earh Software Catalog [3 of 5] 1984 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Whole Earh Software Catalog [4 of 5] 1984 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Whole Earh Software Catalog [5 of 5] 1984 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Publisher's Catalogs: Advertisements for the Whole Earth Software Catalog (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Whole Earth Review - Reviews of [1 of 2] (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Whole Earth Review - Reviews of [2 of 2] (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Whole Earth Review - Clippings (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Whole Earth Catalog (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Next Whole Earth Catalog - Reviews (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Whole Earth Review/ Next Whole Earth Catalog: promotional materials (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Millennium Whole Earth Catalog/Essential WEC: promotional materials (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Whole Earth Epilog 1974 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - "The Fringes of Reason: A Whole Earth Catalog" (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Electronic Whole Earth Catalog (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - "Signal: Communications Tools for the Information Age" (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - "Always Two Steps Ahead" - article (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - "Always Two Steps Ahead" - transcript of interview (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - "Always Two Steps Ahead": tapes [1 of 3], 2 audiotapes: analog (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - "Always Two Steps Ahead": tapes [2 of 3], 2 audiotapes: analog (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - "Always Two Steps Ahead": tapes [3 of 3], 3 audiotapes: analog (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Clippings [1 of 2] (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Clippings [2 of 2] (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - New Games [1 of 4] (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - New Games [2 of 4] (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - New Games [3 of 4] (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - New Games [4 of 4] (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Did She Keep Her People? - Film proposal to NEH (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Proposal by Inform (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - School of Uncommon Courtesy (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Two Cybernetic Frontiers: correspondence, contract, etc. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Two Cybernetic Frontiers / by Stewart Brand. -- New York: Random House, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Clippings about WELL (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Computer Hackers (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - "Texture of Life" and other writings by Stewart Brand (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Clippings about Stewart Brand [1 of 7] (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Clippings about Stewart Brand [2 of 7] (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Clippings about Stewart Brand [3 of 7] (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Clippings about Stewart Brand [4 of 7] (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Clippings about Stewart Brand [5 of 7] (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Clippings about Stewart Brand [6 of 7] (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Clippings about Stewart Brand [7 of 7] (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Awards and certificates (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Flyers and cards (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Weird Earth Review (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 4. Personal Papers
    - Stewart Brand Personnal Correspondence [To be reviewed] (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Julia Brand Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Brand Family Papers (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Series 2. Jay Kinney Editorial files
  - Religion & politics: articles & authors [1 of 3] (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Religion & politics: articles & authors [2 of 3] (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Religion & politics: articles & authors [3 of 3] (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Religion & politics: backscatter not used in No. 40 [1 of 2] (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Religion & politics: backscatter not used in No. 40 [2 of 2] (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Nix: letters for submission [1 of 2] (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Nix: letters for submission [2 of 2] (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Islam section: letters + reference + articles [1 of 2] (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Islam section: letters + reference + articles [2 of 2] (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - This gift must always move: Essay: Manuscript and Correspondence (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Miskitos/Nietschmann: clippings + correspondence [1 of 2] (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Miskitos/Nietschmann: clippings + correspondence [2 of 2] (Box 28, Folder 4)
- Series 3. Reader Correspondence
  - Reader correspondence, 1970 - 1979 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Reader correspondence, 1979 - 1981 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Reader correspondence [1 of 3] 1980 - 1981 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Reader correspondence [2 of 3] 1980 - 1981 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Reader correspondence [3 of 3] 1980 - 1981 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Reader correspondence [1 of 2] 1981 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Reader correspondence [2 of 2] 1981 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Reader correspondence [2 of 2] 1981-1982 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Reader correspondence [1 of 2] 1982 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Reader correspondence [2 of 2] 1982 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Reader correspondence 1982-1983 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Reader correspondence 1988-1990 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Reader correspondence (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Reader correspondence - Art Kleiner Letters and Drawings (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Reader correspondence - Issue no. 24 (Robert Crumb Cover) [1 of 3] (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Reader correspondence - Issue no. 24 (Robert Crumb Cover) [2 of 3] (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Reader correspondence - Issue no. 24 (Robert Crumb Cover) [3 of 3] (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Pet hate column (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Bioregional feedback (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Crime letters (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Reader response to Bold & regular [1 of 6] 1982 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Reader response to Bold & regular [2 of 6] 1982 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Reader response to Bold & regular [3 of 6] 1982 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Reader response to Bold & regular [4 of 6] 1982 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Reader response to Bold & regular [5 of 6] 1982 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Reader response to Bold & regular [6 of 6] 1982 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Series 4. Photographic layouts
  - Photographic layout: artwork & negatives (Oversize 31)
  - Photographic layout: artwork & negatives (Oversize 32)
  - Photographic layout: artwork & negatives (Oversize 33)
- Series 5. Magazines & other publications
  - The updated last Whole Earth Catalog access to tools1974 May, 1 v.: hardbound + 1 v.: paperback (Box 34)
  - CoEvolution (Paris). -- No. 71982 Winter (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - CoEvolution (Paris). -- No. 101982 Autumn (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - CoEvolution (Paris). -- No. 111983 Winter (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Whole Earth Epilog1974, 2 copies (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Whole Earth software catalog for 1986. -- Garden City, N.Y.: Quantum Press / Doubleday, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - The essential Whole Earth catalog. -- New York: Doubleday, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Softtech / ed. by J. Baldwin & Stewart Brand. -- New York: Penguin Books, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 7)
- Series 6. Memorabilia
  - I am Salman Rushdien.d., 1 pin (Box 35)
  - Seeds for thought / ed. by Shinichi Yoshifuku. -- In Japanese (Box 35, Folder 1)
    Originally enclosed in envelope indicating that the volume was sent to Whole Earth byYoshifuku.
  - From Satori to Silicon Valley / Theodore Roszak. -- San Francisco: Don't Call It Frisco Press, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Banner (Box 37)
  - Hand-painted envelope from S. Knutson (Box 37)
  - Life magazine1972 Dec. 15 (Box 37)
    Special issue on the Joys of Christmas
  - Oversize card by Susan Crutchfield (Box 37)
  - Paddington Journal clipping re: Whole Earth philosophy (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous clippings and flyers protesting nuclear power (Box 38)
  - The one millionth copy of the Last Whole Earth catalog: presented to Stewart Brand on December 22, 19711971, 1 v. + 3 l. signed (Box 38)
  - Scrapbook (Box 38)
  - New Games tournament: broadside (Box 39)
  - Photograph of hospital bed (Box 39)
  - Poster of two swine copulating (Box 39)
- Series 7. Audiovisual materials
  - Business Times. Whole Earth1984 Apr. 4, 1 videocassette of 1 (4 min.): sd.; 1/2 in. VHS dub (Box 36, Folder 1)